Which is the Virgin? Which is the Vampire?
Twins of Evil is a horror film directed by John Hough.
While dabbling in Satanism, Count Karstein resurrects Mircalla
Karnstein who initiates him into vampirism.
As a rash of deaths afflicts the village, Gustav the head of Puritan
group leads his men to seek out and destroy the pestilence.
One of his twin nieces has become inflicted with the witchcraft but Gustav's zeal and venom has trapped the innocent
Maria, threatening her with a tortuous execution, whilst Frieda remains free to continue her orgy of evil.
Gustav Weil, played by Peter Cushing.
Dietrich, played by Dennis Price.
Frieda Gellhorn, played by Madeleine Collinson.
Maria Gellhorn, played by Mary Collinson.
Ingrid Hoffer, played by Isobel Black.
Katy Weil, played by Kathleen Byron.
Twins of Evil (also known as Twins of Dracula) is a 1971 British horror film directed by John Hough and starring Peter Cushing, with Damien Thomas,
real-life identical twins: former Playboy Playmates Madeleine and Mary Collinson, Isobel Black, Kathleen Byron, Damien Thomas and David Warbeck.
This was the Collinson sisters' final acting roles.
It is the third (and final) film in the Karnstein Trilogy, based
on the 1872 novella Carmilla by Sheridan Le Fanu.
The film has the least resemblance to the novella and adds
a witchfinding theme to the vampire story.
Much of the interest of the film revolves around the contrasting evil and
good natures of two beautiful sisters, Frieda and Maria.
Unlike the previous two entries in the series, this film
contains only a brief lesbian element.
The film was released in the U.S.
as a double feature with Hands of the Ripper.
The film explores themes of virgin, vampire, twin sister, witch burning, castle.
The tone is dark.